<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>admissioncontroller on KungFu Developer</title>
    <link>https://www.kungfudev.com/tags/admissioncontroller/</link>
    <description>Recent content in admissioncontroller on KungFu Developer</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.kungfudev.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.kungfudev.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.kungfudev.com/tags/admissioncontroller/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CEL for admission controller with ValidatingAdmissionPolicy in K8s 1.26</title>
      <link>https://www.kungfudev.com/posts/cel-for-admission-controller/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kungfudev.com/posts/cel-for-admission-controller/</guid>
      <description>The Kubernetes crew just dropped the latest version, k8s 1.26 a few days ago, and it&amp;rsquo;s packed with some seriously cool new features. One that&amp;rsquo;s catching my eye is CEL for admission control - it allows us to create a ValidatingAdmissionPolicy, taking our cluster security to the next level.
Validating admission policies offer a declarative, in-process alternative to validating admission webhooks.
Validating admission policies use the Common Expression Language (CEL) to declare the validation rules of a policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing a simple K8s admission controller in Go</title>
      <link>https://www.kungfudev.com/posts/implementing-k8s-admission-controller/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.kungfudev.com/posts/implementing-k8s-admission-controller/</guid>
      <description>What is an admission controller? In a nutshell, Kubernetes admission controllers are plugins that govern and enforce how the cluster is used. They can be thought of as a gatekeeper that intercept (authenticated) API requests and may change the request object or deny the request altogether. The admission control process has two phases: the mutating phase is executed first, followed by the validating phase.
Kubernetes admission Controller Phases:
An admission controller is a piece of software that intercepts requests to the Kubernetes API server before the persistence of the object (the k8s resource such as Pod, Deployment, Service, etc&amp;hellip;) in the etcd database, but after the request is authenticated and authorized.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
